<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on Y Violet Guo</title>
    <link>https://violetguos.github.io/categories/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on Y Violet Guo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 06:28:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://violetguos.github.io/categories/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Program MIPS instruction in Verilog</title>
      <link>https://violetguos.github.io/post/cpu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 06:28:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violetguos.github.io/post/cpu/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this project, I have built a multi-cycle processor&amp;rsquo;s instruction set from scratch.
Technical Details  Programmed a multicycle processor in Verilog on a Altera DE-1 FPGA Configured a new Assembly language instruction set with Verilog  Lessons Learned In processor or hardware design, unlike computer software, there is no room for uncertainty. For example, a software engineer may put a button in a not so convenient place for no good reason, but it does not hinder the functionality of the app, just harder to navigate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roulette on FPGA</title>
      <link>https://violetguos.github.io/post/roulette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 01:29:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://violetguos.github.io/post/roulette/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This project was built in the same course as the multi-cycle CPU! As the reader can see, low level hardware can be fun. The two projects share similar principles, but this project has additional displays, such as a computer screen, a speaker for audio output, and we made the roulette as pretty as we could. They all run on the same hardware chip(field programmable gate array, FPGA).
Technical Details  Built a roulette game with PS/2 keyboard, audio output, motor, lego controller, and Altera FPGA Implemented linear feedback shift register in Assembly and C to randomize motor speed and spin time Interfaced keyboard input to prompt user’s bet and display on VGA output with JTAG UART, JPIO ports  Lessons Learned User interface (the screen display, music, and the roulette) makes a difference Creativity matters: engineers should not only focus on the technical details</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>